Archbishop.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
アークビショップ
I thought I asked thee not to call me via that name.
（ﾛｰﾗ）
だから
その名前で呼ぶべからずなのよ
What are you doing here without an escort?
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
護衛もなく こんな所で…
Couldn't you finish this business at the St. George Cathedral?
話なら
聖(セント)ジョージ大聖堂で済むのでは？
I wouldst not be trapped in that old cathedral all year round.
（ﾛｰﾗ）
年がら年中―
あんな古めき聖堂の中になど
取り籠もらないわ
And we can converse while walking, too.
歩みつつも語れるのだし
Well, I don't mind.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
まあ かまいませんけど
You're very narrow-minded, Stiyl.
小さき男なのね ステイル
むしろ この私と共に歩める状況を
耽楽(たんらく)せんとはできないの？
Canst thou not simply enjoy the fact that
thou art walking with someone like me?
Laura Stuart, may I ask you a question?
ローラ＝スチュアート
ひとつだけ よろしいですか？
My, how formal. What is it?
堅きことね　なに？
Why are you talking in such a stupid way?
あなたは どうして そこまでバカな
しゃべり方をしてるんですか？
はぁ… えっ？　おかしいの？
Eh? Dost it sound strange?
I even had a real Japanese person check it!
本物の日本人にも
チェックを入れてもらったのに
And who might that have been?
それは一体 誰なんですか？
He goes by the name of Tsuchimikado Motoharu.
土御門元春(つちみかど もとはる)のヤツなのよ
あんなヤツを
日本人の基準にしないでください
Please don't use that man as an example of a normal Japanese person!
通信用の護符？
A communication talisman?
You know about The Book of the Law, correct?
（ﾛｰﾗ）
あなたは
「法の書」の名は知りたるわね？
A grimoire?
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
魔道書の名ですか？
If I remember correctly, the author was Edward Alexander.
著者は
確か エドワード＝アレクサンダー
It was originally found in the The Roman Church's Vatican Library.
原典は ローマ正教の
バチカン図書館にあったと
しかし
あれは誰にも解読できないと
However, no one was able to decipher it.
Even Index, who contains 103,000 volumes?
（ﾛｰﾗ）
10万3,000冊を記憶したりける
禁書目録でさえね
（ﾛｰﾗ）
その“法の書”を解読できる人間が
現れんとしたら…
What would you say if someone who could read The Book of the Law were to appear?
What?!
なんですって？
There is a Roman Catholic Sister by the name of Orsola Aquinas.
（ﾛｰﾗ）
その者は ローマ正教の修道女で
オルソラ＝アクィナスというさうよ
Do they plan on using The Book of the Law as a method of regaining their power?
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
まさか
「法の書」を勢力争いの道具に？
You needn't worry about that. At least not for now...
（ﾛｰﾗ）
大丈夫　少なくとも今のところはね
Because both the The Book of the Law and Orsola Aquinas have been stolen.
「法の書」とオルソラ＝アクィナス
この２つが
一緒に盗まれたさうだから
How about we discuss more about this inside?
（ローラ）
詳しき説明は
中で掛け合いましょうか
～♪
#02 The Book of
the Law
Second semester is really busy!
（舞夏(まいか)）
２学期というのは
忙しいんだぞ
It's full of festivals like Daihaseisai, Ichihanaransai,
大覇星(だいはせい)祭に一端覧(いちはならん)祭
芸術鑑賞祭に社会科見学祭と
お祭り尽くしなのだからな
Art Appreciation Festival, and Social Studies Field Trip Festival.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
あっ スフィンクス 大丈夫？
Sphinx, are you okay?
But I still have a lot of free time!
There's nothing to do! I'm so bored!
でも 暇だよ
退屈だよ　つまんないよ！
And Touma won't play with me at all!
当麻(とうま)は全然 遊んでくれないし
（猫の鳴き声）
Kamijou Touma has his own life to live.
上条(かみじょう)当麻にも
上条当麻の事情があるんだから
別に 好きで学校に
縛られてるわけではないんだからな
It's not like he wants to be in school.
ンンッ… どうして
舞夏は学校に縛られてないの？
Then why aren't you in school, Maika?
（舞夏）
フフフッ… 私は例外なのだよ
Because I'm an exception.
You see, it's quite normal for a maid to train in the real world.
メイドさんの研修は
実地が基本だからな
じゃ 私もメイドになる！
Then I'll become a maid too!
Then maybe I'll go play with Touma during class!
そして
当麻のクラスに遊びに行くかも
う～ん…
メイドさんの道は厳しいのだぞ
The life of a maid is not an easy one.
It'll be especially difficult for a girl with zero domestic skills.
家庭的スキルゼロの女の子には
難しいな
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
ふ～ん…
あっ！
じゃ 当麻をメイドにする！
Then Touma can be the maid!
That way, Touma can come play with me!
そして
当麻に遊びに来てもらうかも
For Kamijou Touma's sake,
you probably shouldn't suggest that.
そのセリフは 上条当麻には
言わないのが優しさだぞ
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）うん　そうだね
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）えっ？
Yes, that's right.
悪いけど
My apologies...
But it seems that there is no time for either you or him to become maids.
君がメイドになる時間も
ヤツをメイドにする時間もないんだ
"Daihaseisai."
（上条）
“大覇星祭”
"A large sports festival that every school in Academy City participates in."
“学園都市全ての学校が
参加する大運動会”
"In order to observe the large-scale interference between espers,"
（上条）
“能力者同士の大規模干渉の観測を
目的とするもので―”
"students are encouraged to use their powers to the fullest on this day."
“この日かぎりは 能力の
全力使用が推奨されている”か
I see.
わたくし 上条当麻は
とある事情で記憶喪失になっており
I, Kamijou Touma, have lost my memories due to certain circumstances.
そんな大イベントのことすら
全く覚えていないのである
Because of that, I remember absolutely nothing concerning this big event.
So...
さ～てと 晩メシ 何にすっかな
What should I make for dinner?
（舞夏）かかか… 上条当麻！
（上条）うん？
K-K-K-Kamijou Touma!
Huh?
It's an emergency!
緊急事態だぞ！
銀髪シスターが―
The silver-haired Sister was kidnapped by some guy!
何者かに さらわれちゃった！
Huh?
It's a kidnapping! An abduction I tell you!
だから 誘拐だよ　人さらい！
ちょっと待て　どういうことだ？
Hang on.
What are you talking about?
As he left, the kidnapper gave me this...
去り際に誘拐犯が これを…
Dear Kamijou Touma,
“上条当麻
彼女の命が惜しくば―”
If you value her life, then tonight at seven, come to the abandoned theater "Gloaming House" outside Academy City.
“今夜７時に 学園都市の外にある
廃劇場 薄明座(はくめいざ)跡地まで―”
“１人でやって来い”
Come alone.
What was this bastard like?!
そんで そのバカ野郎は
どんな感じのヤツだった？
Hmm... well, he must have been over 180cm tall.
う～ん…
まず身長が180センチを超えててな
His hair was a dark red, and he had
some kind of barcode under his right eye.
髪が真っ赤で
右目の下にバーコードが入ってて
He was smoking a cigarette, and he had lots of earrings on...
くわえタバコで
耳にはピアスが いっぱい
ああ… 大丈夫だぞ 舞夏
Ah, it's fine, Maika.
この犯人は
俺やインデックスの知り合いだ
Index and I both know the guy.
You know the culprit?!
（舞夏）
犯人は知り合い？
動機は ゆがんだラブなのか？
So his motive for this is twisted love?!
Uh, well...
えっ？　あ～ いや…
No, not quite...
そういう意味では…
An Exit... Permit...?
“外出許可証”？
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
大体
状況は分かってもらえたと思うけど
I think you know most of what's going on.
うん
「法の書」が何者かに持ち去られ
The Book of the Law has gone missing.
And the only person capable of deciphering it, Orsola Aquinas, was also kidnapped, right?
それを解読できる者
オルソラ＝アクィナスも―
さらわれたってことだよね？
And apparently the Amakusa Catholics are responsible.
犯人は天草(あまくさ)式十字凄教(せいきょう)らしいって
How on Earth was it taken from that unbelievably secure Vatican Library?
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
あの厳重なバチカン図書館から
一体 どうやって…
The Roman Catholic Church was transporting
The Book of the Law to a Japanese museum.
ローマ正教は「法の書」を
日本の博物館に移送していたのよ
That's ridiculous.
バカげてる　あんな危険な物を…
How could they just transport something so dangerous?
So, is this why the Roman Catholic Church is requesting help from the Church of England?
それで ローマ正教は―
我がイギリス清教へ
協力を打診してきたってわけですか
No.
いいえ
それよりマズしことがありけるの
We have a much bigger problem on our hands.
Which is?
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
何か？
神裂火織(かんざき かおり)と連絡が取れんのよ
I haven't been able to contact Kanzaki Kaori.
Kanzaki was formerly the top of the Amakusa Church.
（ﾛｰﾗ）
神裂は元天草式のトップ
If she were to find out the Amakusa Church and the
Roman Catholic Church have turned against each other...
天草式が ローマ正教と
敵対していると知ったら…
I'd like you to settle this mess before Kanzaki does anything.
神裂が下手を打つ前に
カタをつけてほしいのよ
By any means necessary.
方法は いずれでもかまわないわ
神裂は世界でも20人といない聖人
Kanzaki is a Saint, one of less than twenty in the world.
Don't tell me you want me to fight her...
まさか その神裂と戦えと？
If such a need arises.
（ﾛｰﾗ）
場合が場合ならね
I want you to go to Academy City first.
あなたは
学園都市と接触してちょうだい
And Stiyl, take this with you.
ステイル　これを持ちおいて
うん？　これは…
What's this?
Consider it a small gift for Orsola.
オルソラへのささやかなる贈り物と
いうところかしら
And get in touch with Index.
（ﾛｰﾗ）禁書目録…
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）ンッ…
We'll need a specialist, won't we?
専門家の手は必要でしょう？
Why are you dragging Touma into this?
なんで当麻を巻き込むわけ？
I don't know myself.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
分からないよ
僕だって なんで あんなヤツを…
Why do I have to work with him anyway?
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
それで
天草式の本拠地まで行くの？
So you're going to go all the way to the Amakusa Church's base?
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
いや 状況は少し変わってる
No, the circumstances have changed slightly.
Damn it...
（上条）
くそ…
Where could this "Gloaming House" be?
どこにあんだよ？　薄明座なんて
I don't know the outside of Academy City at all...
学園都市の外は 全然 分かんねえ
シスターさん？
A Sister?
まさか インデックスの
知り合いじゃあるまいな
Don't tell me she's one of Index's acquaintances...
Um...
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）あの…
（上条）ハッ…
Yes? Can I help you?
はい　何か？
Is this the bus to take if I'm heading to Academy City?
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
学園都市に向かうためには―
このバスに乗れば
よいのでございましょうか？
Academy City?
（上条）
学園都市？
いや 学園都市行きのバスはねえよ
There aren't any buses that go to Academy City.
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
はい？
What?
It's not just buses.
バスだけじゃなくて
外からの交通機関は切断されてんだ
All forms of transportation from outside Academy City are cut off.
The gate's in that direction, so if you walk—
あっちにゲートがあるから
そこまで歩いて…
お忙しい中 ご助言いただき
ありがとうございました
Thank you very much for taking time
out of your busy schedule to assist me.
I just told you buses won't take you there!
（上条）
バスはダメだって言ってんだろう！
Oh, yes. You did say that.
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
あっ はい　そうでございましたね
Listen, you walk in that direction
and enter through the gate over there.
だから あっちに歩いて
ゲートから入るの　分かったか？
Understand?
I'm sorry for troubling you.
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
すみません
ご迷惑をかけてしまって
R-Right.
Hey! You're just blowing off
everything I say with a smile, aren't you?!
てめえ！　こっちの説明
笑顔で全部 聞き流してんだろう！
It seems as if something is irritating you.
何かイライラしているように
見えるのでございますね
Well... No, not really.
あっ… いや 別に
If you'll excuse me, it seems that you're sweating quite a bit.
（上条）アッ…
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）失礼ですが
あなたさまは かなりの汗を
かいているのでございますよ
ンッ… サ… サンキュー
T-Thank you.
あっ ところで お前
どうして学園都市に行きたいんだ？
By the way, why are you going to Academy City?
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）あの… 実は私…
（上条）うん？
Well, the truth is...
I'm being pursued.
追われているのでございます
えっ？　追われてる？
You're being pursued?
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）
状況は もうメチャクチャ
The situation's a mess.
Our information's all over the place too.
情報も錯綜(さくそう)しちまって
「法の書」を確保したかどうかも…
I don't even know if we've secured The Book of the Law...
あっ 自己紹介が遅れました
ローマ正教の―
I apologize for my late introduction.
I am Agnese Sanctis from the Roman Catholic Church.
アニェーゼ＝サンクティスと
申します
I see.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
なるほど
So, what kind of spell did the Amakusa Church use?
…で
天草式の連中は どんな術式を？
To be honest, we don't have a precise analysis of it either.
実は こっちも
正確には解析できちゃいないんです
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
天草式の特徴は隠密性だよ
The special trait of the Amakusa Church is secrecy.
天草式は あからさまな
呪文や魔法陣を使わない
The Amakusa Church doesn't use spells or magic circles plainly.
They hide all rituals and incantations in everyday actions and customs.
全ての儀式や術式を―
ふだんの しぐさや作法の中に
隠してしまうから―
Even professional magicians cannot discern their true identity.
プロの魔術師だって
正体は分からないんだよ
フン… 面倒な連中だ
What a bothersome bunch.
Oh, it's Touma!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）あっ 当麻だ！
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）うん？
Orsola Aquinas!
（アニェーゼ）
オルソラ＝アクィナス！
What's the meaning of this?
（上条）
どういうことだよ？　なんで
誘拐ごっこなんてやってんだ？
Why are you pretending to kidnap her?!
フゥ… なんだ　バレてたのか
Oh, so you saw right through it.
I was just going to have you
assist me in finding a missing individual.
いや なに　君に行方不明の人間の
捜索を手伝ってもらおうとね
Finding someone?
捜索？
But it's fine now.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）ああ 大丈夫 大丈夫
（上条）えっ？
So, if you'd be so kind as to hand over that Sister standing beside you...
君の隣にいるシスターを
こっちに引き渡してくれれば
はい？
What?
Like I said.
だから そこのシスターが―
That Sister is the missing individual: Orsola Aquinas.
行方不明の捜し人
オルソラ＝アクィナスだよ
はい お疲れさま
君は もう帰っていいよ
Good job. You're free to go home now.
えっ？　あの…
Um... what do I get in return for
walking around in this blistering heat?
この炎天下の中
歩き回った わたくしめの立場は？
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
だから “お疲れさま”と
言っているじゃないか
Didn't I already thank you?
なんだ？　かき氷でも
おごってほしいのかい？
What, do you want me to treat you to some shaved ice?
（握りしめる音）
（上条）これまではさ…
And here I was, thinking that I'd try to get along with you even if our personalities don't match.
ウマが合わないと知りながらも
仲良くやっていこうと思ってたんだ
Up until now, at least!
ああ！　この瞬間まではな！
（煙を吐く音）
ウワッ！
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
君は
もしかして かまってほしいのか？
Could it be you want me to care about you?
あいにく 僕は―
Unfortunately, I cannot fill the empty sadness within you. Nor do I want to.
君の寂しさを埋めることは
できないし したくもない
Now hurry up and hand Orsola over to Agnese.
さっさと
オルソラをアニェーゼに引き渡せ
そういや 誰かに追われてるって
言ってたけど
That's right, you said that you were being pursued earlier...
うん？　どうしたんだ？　オルソラ
What's wrong, Orsola?
（建宮(たてみや)）
いやいや　そう簡単に
引き渡されては困るのよな
Well, well...
We can't just let you hand her over so easily, can we?
Orsola Aquinas...
（建宮）
オルソラ＝アクィナス
お前はローマ正教に戻るよりも―
I can guarantee your life will be far more meaningful with the Amakusa Church than with the Roman Catholic Church.
我ら天草式と共にあったほうが―
有意義な暮らしを
送ることができるとよ
天草式？
The Amakusa Church!
Orsola!
オルソラ！
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）あっ…
Don't, Touma!
（上条）
ダメだよ 当麻！
Fire is in my hand.
我が手には炎
その形は剣(つるぎ)　その役は…
Thy shape is a sword, and thy purpose is—
I was too late...
遅かったみたいだ
Hey, Stiyl, you'd better explain this
entire thing to me from beginning to end.
おい ステイル
イチから説明する気あんだろうな？
Actually, I could use an explanation, too.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
説明なら
僕のほうが求めたいくらいだね
The Book of the Law is a grimoire
written in a code that nobody can decipher.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
「法の書」っていうのは―
世界の誰にも解読できない暗号で
書かれた魔道書なの
It's said that you can attain tremendous power once you can decipher it.
解読すれば―
絶大な力を手にすることができると
いわれているけど
So, uh...
（上条）
あのさ
それって
そんな価値がある物(もん)なのか？
Is that book really that valuable?
Rumor has it that the world ruled by Christian religion will come to an end if one were to use it.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
もし それが使われれば―
十字教が支配する今の世界が
終わりを告げるとまでいわれている
Why not just burn a book like that?
そんな本 燃やしちまえば…
Grimoires cannot be burned.
魔道書は燃えない本なの
At best they can only be sealed away.
せいぜい
封印するのが精いっぱいなんだよ
ハァ… あっ えっと…
Oh, uh...
I'd like to start by explaining the situation...
状況の説明を
始めちまいたいんですけど
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）アッ！
（上条）ウワッ！
Touma!
あっ 当麻！
イヤーッ！　ちょっと！
ダメ やめて！　離れて！
Wait!
No, stop! Go away!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
当麻…
Touma, don't you think you're going a little overboard with this prank?!
それは いたずらとしての限界を
超えてるかも！
Stop getting aroused during work.
仕事中に発情するな
At the moment, Orsola Aquinas is in the hands of the Amakusa Church.
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）
現状 オルソラ＝アクィナスは
確実に 天草式の手にあります
今回の件に出張ってる天草式の数は
推定で50人弱
We estimate fifty people from the Amakusa Church are involved in this.
There's a possibility that they might even be on the surface.
今は
地上へ上がっちまってる可能性も…
In other words, you don't know anything?
つまり 何にも
分かんないってことなのかな？
魔力の痕跡から
天草式の動向を追っていやすが
We're tracking the movements of the
Amakusa Church from their traces of magic, but...
The Amakusa Church specializes in escaping and hiding.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
天草式は 隠れること
逃げることに特化した集団
You won't catch them so easily.
簡単には捕まらないよ
B-But there's no way they could get past our net.
でも ウチの包囲網を
突破しちまえる方法なんて…
Special Movement Method: Map Pilgrimage.
特殊移動法 “縮図巡礼”
This spell is limited to Japan only.
日本国内限定の術式なんだけどね
Basically, there are forty-seven
special whirlpools spread across Japan.
簡単に言えば
日本中に特殊な渦が47か所あって
This "map magic" allows one to move freely between them.
その間を
自由に行き来できる地図の魔術
It's all over for us if they jump using a whirlpool!
渦を使って飛ばれたら
もう終わりだ
何をのんびりしてんですか！
What are you taking your time for?!
Because there's no need to hurry.
急ぐ必要はないからだよ
Huh?
Map Pilgrimage is heavily dependent on the movement of the stars.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
縮図巡礼には
星の動きが大きく影響してくるの
It can only be used at a certain time.
決まった時間じゃないと
特殊移動法は使えない
The only time the special movement method can be used is directly after midnight,
特殊移動法の使用制限解除は
日付変更直後だから―
so we have about four and a half hours left.
まだ４時間半くらいの余裕はあるよ
Anyway... Touma, let me see that whatchamacallit, that map thing.
それから
当麻 地図の出るピコピコ貸して
Okay.
ほら
Here.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
この包囲網の中で
使える渦は１か所だけ
In this net, there's only one whirlpool they can use.
Right here.
ここだよ
（上条）
さてと…
Well, then...
何か手伝えることはっと…
Is there anything I can help out with?
（ﾙﾁｱ）
だから あれほど言ったでしょう
しっかり確認しなさいって
How many times must I tell you to double-check your work?!
（ｱﾝｼﾞｪﾚﾈ）
はい　すみません
Yes Ma'am. I'm sorry...
Looks like Sisters have it rough too.
なんか
シスターさんも大変なんだな
うん？　インデックス用のテントか
Index's tent...
Huh? She's not here.
あれ？　いない
…たく どこ行ったんだ？
（物音）
Sheesh, where did she run off to?
Found you!
あれか！
Goddamn it!
ちくしょう！
Index!
インデックス！
The Amakusa Church!
天草式？　あっ…
えっ？　ちょ… ちょっと
H-Hey...
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）あれ… あれ…
（上条）えっ？
T-That...
Oh, it's just a slug.
なんだ　ナメクジじゃねえか
ナ… ナメクジ…
S-Slug...
H-Hey!
お… おい！　しっかりしろよ！
Get a hold of yourself!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）当麻？
（上条）ハッ…
Touma?
Uh... I-I just thought that the
Amakusa Church was invading, and uh...
い… いや　てっきり 天草式が
攻めてきたのかと思って その…
Huh?
えっ？　ちょ…
ちょっと落ち着け インデックス
H-Hey, calm down, Index...
This doesn't suit you!
こんなの
あなたのキャラじゃないですよ
You don't usually act like this!
いつもの あなたなら
こうじゃないでしょう？
How about just doing what you normally—
いつもみたいに 思い切って…
なあ　ステイル
Hey, Stiyl...
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
何だい？　僕は今
とてもイライラしているんだ
What?
I'm extremely irritated right now.
Who do you like?
お前の好きな子 誰だよ？
なあ　ステイル
Hey, Stiyl?
尊敬する女性は エリザベス１世で
好みのタイプは 聖女マルタだ
The woman I respect is Elizabeth I, and my type is Saint Martha.
The Amakusa Christian Church...
天草式十字凄教って あれだろう？
神裂火織が前にいた…
That's the one Kanzaki Kaori was in, right?
誰から聞いた？　土御門か？
Who did you hear that from?
Tsuchimikado?
だったら 天草式ってのは
神裂の仲間なんだろう？
Then that means the Amakusa Church
still communicates with Kanzaki, right?
Knowing that... are you still going to fight?
それでも… やるのか？
I will.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
やるよ
You know, I've decided to do anything to protect that girl.
僕はね あの子を守るためなら
何でもやるって決めているんだ
That means killing anyone in my way.
だから 誰でも殺す
I'll burn them alive, and char their bodies if they're already dead.
生きたままでも燃やす
死体になっても焼き尽くす
I vowed this a long time ago.
ずっと昔に誓ったんだよ
Even if that girl forgot everything,
I won't forget anything that happened.
たとえ あの子が
全てを忘れてしまったとしても―
僕は何ひとつ忘れず
君のために生きて 死ぬと
Even if it means putting my life on the line.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
もう寝ろ
Go to sleep already.
Stiyl...
ステイル？
...is still there, which means...
じゃないってことは…
えっ？　こ… こら
ちょっと待て インデックス
H-Hey! Stop that, Index!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）ウ～ン… なに 当麻？
（上条）えっ？
What, Touma?
（上条）
ゲッ！　アニェーゼ？
Agnese?!
Papa...
Papa?
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）夢…
（上条）えっ？
Dream.
これは夢　だから 当麻に
どれだけ かみついても大丈夫
This is a dream.
And because it's a dream, I can bite Touma as much as I want.
日ごろの不満を
思いっきり ぶつけても大丈夫！
I can express all of my discontent!
ちょ… ちょっと待て インデックス
これは 紛れもなくリアル…
W-Wait, Index. This is undoubtedly real—
（上条）
不幸だーっ！
Such misfortune!
（五和(いつわ)）
教皇代理！
Acting Pope.
（五和）
縮図巡礼の準備 全て整いました
We've completed preparations for the Map Pilgrimage.
（建宮）
さて…
Well, then...
神裂火織 お前に見せてやろうぞ
Kanzaki Kaori, I'll show you...
多角宗教融合型 十字教術式
What the multi-religion incorporated Christian Church—the Amakusa Christian Church—looks like now!
天草式十字凄教の今の姿を
～♪
Next Episode
（上条）
渦へと突入する俺たちとローマ正教
We jump into the whirlpool with the Roman Catholic Church.
After we meet, Tatemiya Saiji speaks of an unbelievable truth.
激突の果てに
建宮斎字(さいじ)が語った衝撃の事実
And the fate of Orsola is...
そして オルソラは…
次回 「天草式」
Next time: "The Amakusa Church."
When science and magic cross paths, this epic will begin!
科学と魔術が交差するとき
物語は始まる